■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
《南方公園》第18季  第6集
"免費才怪"
I'm going down to south park
gonna have myself a time
Friendly faces everywhere
humble folks without temptation
Going down to south park
gonna leave my woes behind
Ample parking day or night
people shouting howdy neighbor
Heading on out to south park
gonna see if I can't unwind
I like girls with big vaginas
I like girls with big fat titties
Come on down to south park
and meet some friends of mine.
翻譯：西西   胡好時   foxap   慕容龍飛   半半   CS小明漫畫家
凱爾  凱爾  等等
Oh, hey, Kyle. Kyle, hang on a sec.
校對：吃貨丁小七    時間軸：marktaotao    靈媒
吉米  早上好  怎么了
Hey, Jimmy. What's up?
沒怎么  我就是想確保
Not much. I just wanted to make sure
你已經知道這個棒呆了的消息
you've heard the f-f-fantastic news.
后期：吃貨丁小七      總監：吃貨丁小七
"泰倫斯和菲利普"又出新的手機游戲了
There's a new "Terrance and Phillip" mobile game,
那游戲巨好玩
and it's so amazing and incredibly fun.
真的嗎
Oh, really?
是啊  而且最棒的是
Yeah. And the most unbelievable part.
游戲完全免費
It's totally free!
你應該現在就把它下載到手機里
You should download it to your phone right now.
想想看
I mean, come on.
既然是免費的  為什么不玩呢
If it's free, why wouldn't you?
聽起來很棒
Cool.
謝謝  吉米  我會下載的
Thanks, Jimmy. Well, I'll check it out.
心動不如行動哦
You betcha, pal.
泰倫斯和菲利普  把你的錢給我們
全新的"泰倫斯和菲利普"手機游戲
The "Terrance and Phillip" mobile game.
在這個游戲里  你們就是泰倫斯和菲利普
In this game, you are Terrance and Phillip.
你能收集到所有的加拿大硬幣嗎
Can you collect all the Canadian coins?
收集到一個硬幣  你能收集到更多嗎
That's one coin. Can you collect more?
你已經收集了十個加拿大硬幣  恭喜你
You've collected 10 Canadian coins! Congratulations.
10個硬幣  恭喜你
你真棒
Hey, you're really good at this, guy.
-搞什么啊  -恭喜你  凱爾
- What? - Congratulations, Kyle.
有了加拿大硬幣  你可以購買商品
With Canada coins, you can buy stuff
并且幫助泰倫斯和菲利普重建加拿大
and help Terrance and Phillip rebuild Canada.
四處跑動  收集更多的硬幣
Run around and collect more coins,
或者直接購買硬幣
or better yet, buy them in bulk.
皇家銀行
200個加拿大硬幣  49美分  550個加拿大硬幣  5美金
1100個加拿大硬幣  10美金  1650個加拿大硬幣  15美金
2500個加拿大硬幣  20美金  5700個加拿大硬幣  50美金
你想購買多少加拿大硬幣呢
How man Canadian coins would you like to buy?
這太蠢了
This is stupid!
最便宜的那個只要49美分
Well, it's just $.49 for the cheapest one.
你用49美分買了200個加拿大硬幣
You bought 200 Canadian coins for $.49!
200個加拿大硬幣  49美分  購買
你真棒
You're amazing!
你剛剛購買了楓國幣  你真棒
現在  用楓國幣來重建加拿大吧
Now use that canadough to help rebuild Canada.
點擊此處以修建醫院
Click to build a hospital here.
點擊此處修建醫院
還是很弱智  我居然還花了49美分
It's still stupid, and now I paid 49 cents for it!
你們兩個傻逼在做什么呢
What are you two boners doing?
我們在玩"泰倫斯和菲利普"的免費游戲
We're playing the "Terrance and Phillip" freemium game!
我已經玩過了  蠢透了
I played that thing. It's fucking dumb.
而且我還花了5美金
I ended paying like five bucks.
這個傻逼游戲是誰弄的
Who made this crap?!
加拿大手機游戲部
簡直棒呆了
Oh, it's teriffic!
一天之內就多了20萬美金
That's $200,000 more American dollars in just one day!
我們要賺翻了
Where is the roof on this thing?
誰讓你們未經我們允許
What's the big idea making a mobile game
就開發手機游戲的
without our approval?!
是泰倫斯和菲利普啊
Oh, Terrance and Phillip.
加拿大最受歡迎的兩個人今天過得怎么樣
How are Canada's two favorite buddies?
誰給你權力開發這個
What gives you the right to make a stupid
傻逼的"泰倫斯和菲利普"手機游戲了
"Terrance and Phillip" mobile game?
你以為你是誰啊
Who do you think you are?
我只是加拿大的王子而已
Oh, I'm only the Prince of Canada.
而他剛好是手機游戲部的部長
And this happens to be the Minister of Mobile Gaming.
我們以為你們會
We thought you would be pleased
對此游戲的質量感到滿意
with the quality of the mobile game.
這根本就是史上最傻逼的游戲
It's the dumbest game ever.
里面唯一能做的就是收集再花掉楓國幣
All you do is collect and spend canadough.
我們知道這個游戲不怎么樣
We know the game's not great.
但是誰管它  它是免費的
But who cares? It's free!
這游戲根本就不免費
But it's not free.
如果你們這里收40美分那里收50美分
If you charge $.40 here and $.50 there
這游戲就不是免費
then it's not free!
他們已經看穿了我們的把戲
They see through the charade.
你覺得他們看穿了
You think so?
是的  我認為他們已經知道了
I think they see through the charade, yes.
而且我很確定他們也能聽見我們說話
I'm pretty sure they can hear us, too.
好吧  去他的
All right. Fuck it.
反正你們已經看穿我們的把戲了
You've seen through the charade,
那其它的事情你們應該也知道了  謎團揭曉
so you might as well know everything. Charade up!
過去的游戲  花錢→享受
讓我跟你們解釋一下
Allow me to explain the science
微支付免費游戲背后的科學
behind micro-pay freemium gaming.
多年來  游戲的概念都很簡單
For years, the concept behind gaming was simple,
過去的游戲  花錢→享受
你花錢買這個游戲  然后享受它帶來的快樂
you pay for the game, and you enjoy.
現在有了手機應用  我們可以
With mobile apps, we now have the ability
開發出無聊透頂的游戲
to make games that are boring and stupid,
但如果你花錢買獎勵
but if you pay for incentives,
你就得到了獎賞
you are rewarded.
"完全免費"  拉丁語
完全免費里面的"完全"
Freemium, the "mium"
在拉丁語里是"并不"的意思
is Latin for "not really".
拉丁語  "并不免費"
說起來很簡單
It's a simple cycle,
就是一個基于角色扮演游戲的循環
and never-ending loop based on RPGs.
角色扮演游戲循環
探索→收集→付款→升級
探索  收集  付款  升級
Explore, collect, spend, improve.
其他游戲使用的是"XP"概念
But where are those just use the concept of X.P.,
又名經驗值
or experience points,
而我們介紹了現金小額支付的概念
we've introduced the idea of micro-paying with money.
小額支付
探索  收集  付款  升級
現金  現金  現金  現金
Money, money, money, money,
這就是當下流行趨勢
it's what everyone is doing.
免費增值游戲時下最夯
Freemium games are what's now,
帶來無限樂趣
and it's all just a lot of harmless fun.
你麻煩大了  斯坦利
You're in big trouble, Stanley.
你能跟我們解釋下你是如何
Can you explain to us how you managed
在手機軟件上花了486刀么
to spend $489 on a mobile app?
對不起嘛  我又沒想到會花那么多
I'm sorry. I didn't realize I spent that much.
你沒想到么
You didn't realize?
加拿大金幣是什么玩意
What are Canadian coins?
你買了加拿大金幣就能擁有加拿大
You buy Canadian coins so you have Canada.
斯坦  我是用音樂創作讓生活質量好了點
Stan, just because I make a good living with my music
但不代表你可以揮霍在楓國幣
doesn't mean you can blow it all on Canadough.
我會還給你的  好嘛
I'll pay you back for it, ok?
怎么還
How?
我怎么知道  我會想辦法的啦
I don't know. I'll figure it out.
神煩
Jesus Christ!
你能信他么
Can you believe him?
他知道自己花了多少錢
He knew how much he was spending.
也知道自己惹麻煩了  但他不在乎
He knew he'd get in trouble. But it didn't matter.
我不想提的  但他真像他爺爺
I hate to say it, but this is a lot like his grandpa.
什么意思
What do you mean?
老爸一直有賭癮
Dad's always had a gambling problem.
他有成癮傾向
He's got total addiction tendencies.
他會不會把惡習遺傳給了斯坦啊
Could he have somehow passed those demons down to Stan?
是哦  你好像也有類似的毛病
Well, and you certainly have some of those problems, too,
比如酒癮
with drinking.
我是有過  但我克制住了
I had a problem, but I was able to stop.
現在我只喝不含谷蛋白的啤酒和紅酒
Now I only drink gluten-free beer and wine.
至于斯坦
But with Stan,
我認為他體內有股惡勢力
I think there's some darkness inside him
阻止他停手
that doesn't allow him to stop.
"免費增值游戲"
成功準則
總之成功的免費增值游戲
And so, in conclusion, the successful freemium game
需要遵守五條準則
is based on five principles --
簡單  游戲周期
用簡單的游戲周期來吸引玩家
Entice the player with a simple Game loop,
用很多牛逼閃閃的獎勵和贊賞
use lots of flashing "Cha-chings" and compliments
獎賞
"你最棒了"
來讓玩家自我感覺良好
to make the player feel good about themselves,
虛擬貨幣
訓練玩家使用虛擬貨幣
train the players to spend your fake currency,
邀請玩家使用真實貨幣
offer the players way to spend real currency
真假交易
買進虛擬貨幣
for your fake currency --
他們就會忘記自己在花錢了
so they'll forget their spending money.
并且讓游戲重點放在等待
And make the game about waiting,
等待游戲
無需等待
卻讓玩家付款取消等待
but let the player pay not to wait.
這就是發大財之道
It's a sure-fire way to make lots of money.
發大財
我們明白小額支付
We understand micro-paying.
但難道不能讓游戲的設計
But can't the game hidden inside the charade
至少有趣點么
just at least be fun?
不行  不行
No, no!
它只能勉強算有趣
It has to be just barely fun.
勉強算有趣
小額支付
有趣
如果游戲太有趣了  就沒有理由
If the game was too fun, then there would be no reason
通過小額支付讓它變得更有趣了
to micro-pay in order to make it more fun.
這是什么
What's this?
當然是你們的支票啊  每人一千萬美金
Your checks, of course, for $10 million American dollars, each.
所以這  每個人都這么做么
So this is -- everyone is doing this?
人人都這么做
Everyone is doing it.
事情就這么簡單么
It's just the way things are going?
就這么簡單
It's the way things are going.
我想如果每人一次都只付四十美分的話
Well, I guess if everyone's just paying $.40 at a time,
也不是什么大事
it can't be that bad.
你們好
Oh, hey, guys.
你丫今天翹課啦
You... missed school today?
對啊  今天狀態不是極好
Yeah, I just wasn't feeling the best.
你整天都在玩"泰倫斯和菲利普免費游戲"么
Did you play the "Terrance & phillip Freemium" game all day?
是啊  我臥病在床
Well, yeah. I was sick in bed.
還能做什么
What else am I gonna do?
你今天花了多少錢  斯坦
How much money did you micro-pay today, Stan?
一分都沒
Nothing.
哥們兒  我買了十刀的楓國幣呢
Dude, I bought like $10 worth of Canadough.
但快看
But check it out.
我解鎖了多倫多體育場
I unlocked the stadium in Toronto.
你花了十塊錢和八個小時來解鎖個體育場
You spent $10 and eight hours to unlock a stadium.
這有比你們玩的電玩腦殘那么多嗎
You guys, is it that much dumber than video games you play?
有
Yes.
這只是一個消磨時間的游戲而已
It's just, like, something to kill some time.
就像吉米說的  這是一種高級發呆模式
Like Jimmy said, it's a cool way to zone out.
等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
吉米跟你說的這個游戲的嗎
Jimmy told you about this game?
吉米也跟我說了這個游戲
Jimmy told me about his game.
肯尼  誰告訴你的這個游戲
Kenny, who told you about this game?
吉米
Jimmy.
老天  臥
Dude. What...
槽
The...
瑪
Fuck.
小屁孩  過來
Hey, kid. Come over here.
就是你  過來  瞧瞧這個
Yeah, come on over. Check this out.
想找點樂子嗎
You lookin' to have some fun?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
"泰倫斯和菲利普"手游
The "Terrance & Phillip" mobile game.
酷小孩都在玩
All the cool kids are using it.
沒聽說過
I don't know.
別這樣  先試試
Come on. Just try it out.
你可以當泰倫斯或菲利普或都當
You can be Terrance, or Phillip, or both.
你可以到處走動收集加拿大幣來建新東西
You can walk around and collect Canada cash to build new stuff.
無聊的時候玩這個最棒了
It's the perfect thing if you're bored.
而且最棒的地方就是它是免費的
And honestly, the best part about it is it's free.
想想看
I mean, come on.
為什么不下載下來玩一玩呢
Why wouldn't you download it and try it out?
吉米  咱能談談不
Hey, uh, Jimmy, can we talk?
沒問題  伙計  記得試試  小屁孩
Well, sure, fellas. Anyway, be sure to check it out, kid
老兄  你在搞什么啊
Dude, what are you doing?
沒事亂逛  你們想干什么
Just hanging out. What are you up to?
你不能再向別人推薦這個應用了
You need to stop recommending that app to people.
大家都說是從你這聽說這個應用的
Look, everyone we know says they heard about it from you.
我只不過覺得這應用不錯  僅此而已
I just think it's a fabulous app. That's all.
不錯個鬼  他媽的傻翻天了
It's not a fabulous app. It's fucking stupid.
那讓我問你個問題  吉米
Let me ask you something, Jimmy.
升到第二級入手安大略金礦后會發生什么
What happens on level two after you get the Ontario nugget?
好吧  好吧  我沒玩過這個游戲
All right, all right. I never played it.
我避免接觸這種東西
I stay away from this stuff.
那你還給別人推薦
You just push it on other people?
是他們付錢讓我這么干的
They pay me to!
誰  吉米  是誰給你付的錢
Who, Jimmy! Who pays you?!
你們倆干得不錯
You've both done an amazing job.
新醫院  新街區
New hospitals, new neighborhoods,
資金全由一個免費游戲提供
all funded by one freemium game.
聽著
Uh, listen.
我們談過這件事了
We've been talking it over,
我們對這個免費的玩意兒沒什么好感
and we really aren't comfortable with this freemium thing.
怎么回事
What is the matter?
它欺騙消費者  我們要維護自己的品牌
It seems dishonest, and we have a brand to protect.
可你們看看我們正在興建的這些東西
But just look at all the things we're getting to build.
很快加拿大就會和密歇根一樣先進發達
Soon, Canada will be as advanced and developed as Michigan.
我們擔心有些人會玩上癮
We're just worried that some people will abuse the game
在游戲中投入他們根本負擔不起的錢
and start spending more money than they can afford.
不  我們當然不想讓那種情況發生
Oh, no! Well, we certainly wouldn't want that.
我有個主意
I have an idea.
我們何不從我們賺取的數十億里
How about we take some of the billions of dollars
拿出一部分來發起一個運動
we are making and we start a campaign
教導大家玩游戲要適度呢
to teach everyone to play the game in moderation?
你覺得會有用嗎
Do you really think that would help?
當然啦  酒水業一直都這么干
Of course! The alcohol industry does it all the time.
你  朋友
You. Friends.
快樂  喝酒
Fun. Drink.
靚妞  你是靚仔
Hot girls. You're hot.
多喝點  豪車
Drink more. Expensive cars.
美臀  喝酒
Ass. Drink.
美臀  鈔票
Ass. Money.
身穿燕尾服  三人行  伏特加  逼
You in a tuxedo. Threesomes. Vodka. Pussy.
喝  喝  喝  你  喝  維加斯
Drink, drink, drink! You! Drink! Vegas!
快樂  屄
Fun! Pussy!
你身穿燕尾服操翻這個美女
You in a tuxedo fuck this girl.
伏特加  喝  喝  喝
Vodka! Drink, drink, drink!
喝光光  操你媽逼  燕尾服多多
Drink it all, you fucking pussy! More tuxedo!
車多多  逼多多
More cars! More pussy!
伏特加多多  喝  喝  喝
More vodka! Drink, drink, drink!
飲酒需謹慎
請謹慎飲酒
Please drink responsibly.
三毛賭場
跟上  這邊  斯坦
Come on. This way, Stan.
我想讓你看看  在這呢
I want you to see this. There you go.
這是你爺爺  他坐在老虎機前面
That's your grandpa. He sits at that slot machine
不動腦子地讓錢一點點地流走
and mindlessly drains money away a little bit at a time.
是不是很耳熟  那些聲音和燈光
Sound familiar? All the little sounds and lights
都調試過的  好讓他一直坐在那破機器前
are calculated to keep him sitting at that stupid machine.
快點  老爸  咱們回家
Come on, Dad. We're going home.
滾蛋
Ah, go away.
你知道你對你孫子影響多不好嗎
Do you know what you've done to your grandson?
你這一套烏煙瘴氣都把他傳染了
You've infected him with your bullshit.
你說啥呢
What are you talking about?
我真是不理解你們到底是什么問題
I just don't understand what I wrong with you two.
玩那東西到底有什么意思
What is the joy that this stuff possibly brings you?
它就是...
It's just...
很有趣
It's fun.
是啊  它很有趣
Yeah, it's fun.
有趣個鬼
It's not fun!
你們倆心中有魔鬼要去不斷地滿足
You two have demons you're trying to compensate for.
那你呢  你不是拿著一杯酒要喝嗎
Well, what about you? You're having a glass of wine.
我不是拿著一杯酒要喝
I'm not having a glass of wine.
我有六杯  這叫品酒  很有品位
I'm having six. It's called a tasting, and it's classy.
老爸  我沒上癮
Dad, I'm not addicted.
我可以不玩  我只是喜歡玩而已
I can stop. I just like playing it,
但是我可以不玩  我會證明的
but I don't have to. I'll prove it.
好  要是他不玩了我也停手
Yeah, and if he stops, I'll stop.
好吧  要是你們倆都不玩了
All right. And if you two stop,
那么我們就不存在任何問題了
then we won't have a problem anymore.
淡淡的  咽下后有絲絲櫻桃味
Earthy, bold, hint of cherry after-tones.
別人有空的時候要做什么
Is it my responsibility what people decide to do
是我的責任嗎
with their f-f-free time?
我只是一個中間人
I was just the middleman.
就算不通過我
People were going to
他們也會通過其他的地方知道
learn about the game somewhere if not from Me.
又不是我編了這個游戲
I'm not the one who made it.
可是你收了加拿大政府的錢
You accepted money from the Canadian government
煽動我們來玩免費游戲  他們為什么要這樣
to push a Freemium game on us. Why would they do that?
你要怎么讓人沉迷于它失去控制呢
How do you get people addicted to crack?
你免費贈送  給人家一點甜頭
You give it away for free. You give away a little taste,
然后  有的人就不能停下來了
And then -- and then some people can't stop themselves.
現在斯坦完全迷上了你推薦的這鬼東西
and now Stan is so consumed by the shit by you've been pushing
他自己還屁都不知道
that he can't even see through it!
你怎么能出賣朋友吶
How could you sell out your friends?!
我需要錢  好吧
I need the money, all right!
我下載了"美味的寶石森林"  因為它免費
I downloaded yum yum sparkly gem forest because it was free.
我喜歡玩亮閃閃的寶石
I loved the sparkling little Gems,
還有得到它們時發出的聲音
the sounds they made when I got new ones.
接著我第一次用了程序內購買
Then I made my first in-app purchase.
不知不覺我就花光了零用錢
Before I knew it, I had spent my allowance,
接著是我過生日的錢  還失去了我的拐杖
then my birthday money. I lost my crutches!
你拐杖還在這里吶
You have your crutches.
這是殘疾人用來打比喻的
It's a figure of speech with Crippled people.
說失去手腳沒那么有說服力
We'd say we lost an arm and a leg, but they ain't worth much.
說的有道理
That makes sense.
你說這些游戲都是故意這樣做的嗎
You're saying these games do this on purpose?
只要你一不玩  免費游戲就會發提醒
Why do you think freemium games send you those text
你覺得它這樣是為什么呢
notifications when you haven't played in a while?
這就是觸發器
It's called a trigger --
觸動你上癮的腦袋
a quick image to trigger the addict's brain.
他們明明白白地知道這些
They know exactly what they're
嗨  兄弟
Hey, buddy!
來吧  伙計
Come on, guy!
來玩吧朋友  你有一個新好友
Come back, friend. You've got new buddies, guy.
我們剛給你送出五千個加拿大幣
We've just given you 5,000 Canadian coins.
盡情享受吧
Enjoy your canadough.
免費
Free?
你到底怎么了啊  斯坦
What is wrong with you, Stan?
你說過不會再買楓國幣了
You said you stopped buying canadough.
我沒想到用了那么多錢
I didn't think I spent that much.
我點了幾個在線支付  它們就累加起來了
I-I clicked on a few micropays and it just kind of added up.
26000美元
$26,000?
約16萬人民幣
你知道我要寫多少首歌
Do you know how many songs I have to write
才賺得回這么多錢嗎
to make back that much money?
一首
One.
跟你說也是白說
Oh, it's just nothing to you,
不  不是的
No. It's not.
你要知道  你的腦子里
You need to realize that you have something in your brain
有從你爺爺那里遺傳來的東西
that you somehow inherited from your grandpa
才讓你成這樣子了  好吧
that makes you act this way, okay?
我不明白你怎么喝著酒還好意思說這種話
I don't know how you can say that when you're standing here
我不是在喝酒
I am not chugging beer.
我在取一些無谷蛋白德國拉格啤酒
I'm sampling a flight of gluten-free
和法國紅酒進行混合
German lagers with a French wine pairing.
這叫"斯摩格酒"  很高大上的
It's called a smorgaswein and it's elegantly cultural.
好吧  我需要幫助
Okay, I need help.
我覺得自己有點異樣  兄弟們
There is something different about me, you guys.
我知道這個游戲很傻逼
I know the game is stupid,
而且我一點也不覺得游戲好玩
and It actually isn't even fun anymore.
我搞不明白
I don't understand.
兄弟們  能給我和斯坦一點時間嘛
Fellas, could I have a minute with Stan please.
當然  走吧兄弟們
Sure.Come on, guys.
這是我的錯  斯坦
This is my fault, Stan.
我就不該告訴你說這游戲好贊
I should have never told you the game was f-f-f-fa-fantastic.
這不是你的錯  是我家族的原因
It's not your fault. It's something to do with my family.
就像一個詛咒
It's like a curse.
我知道這些事很難理解
I know this stuff is hard to understand.
相信我我知道  我也上癮了
Trust me, I know. I'm an addict, too.
但是  我得到了幫助
But I get help.
怎么辦
How?
那些讓人上癮的程序的說法都是真的
What all the addiction programs say is true --
你得尋求更高的力量  斯坦
You've got to reach out to a higher power, Stan.
你要雙膝跪地  然后說
You've got to get down on your knees and you've got to say,
我有問題
"I Have a problem."
然后你得尋求它的幫助
And you've got to ask that power for help.
我們得找到一種方式告訴所有的人
We have to find a way to get the word out.
大家要知道推銷者是被雇來
People need to know pushers are being hired
專門利用容易上癮的人的
to take advantage of people with addiction problems.
我們必須找到一個方法  偷溜進新聞公司
There has to be a way we can get to the news company
然后借用他們的電視信號
and sneak in and somehow borrow their TV signal.
如果我們能偽裝自己成什么  接著
If we could disguise ourselves as something ridiculous, then
好啦  弄好了
Okay, it's done.
什么弄好了
What's done?
消息發出去了
The word is out.
"泰倫斯和菲利普”雇人利用上癮習慣賺錢
"Terrance and phillip hire pushers to make money off Addicts."
我發推特了
I tweeted it.
已經火了
It's trending.
加拿大手機游戲部門
狗娘養的
You son of a bitch!
你付錢給推銷者引誘人上癮玩免費游戲嗎
You paid pushers to get addicts hooked on our freemium game?
你說啥
You what?
等等  泰倫斯和菲利普
Now hold on, Terrance & Philip,
推銷一款手游何錯之有啊
there's nothing wrong with promoting a mobile game.
但是有意去讓它迎合人性的弱點
But there's something very wrong
那就是大錯特錯了
with knowingly making it appeal to human weaknesses!
你造的不是手游  是一款成癮機
You didn't build a mobile game, you built an addiction machine.
手游大臣  到底是怎么回事
Minister of mobile gaming, what is this all about?
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
你們又把山人的妙計識破了
You've seen through the charade again.
就讓我來揭秘免費游戲的真正面目吧
Let me explain how freemium games really work.
真相是
The truth is,
免費游戲總利潤
沒掏錢
掏錢——手游利潤
下載了免費增值游戲的人中
a very small percentage of people
只有很小一部分是忠實的人民幣玩家
who download freemium games ever pay anything for them.
所以重點在于找到花錢最多的玩家
It's all aboot finding the heaviest users
并想辦法從他們身上榨取到最多的錢
and extracting the most amount of cash from them.
免費真相
利潤=1%的玩家
這就是為啥上癮的人會在
That's how you get addicts to pay 200 bucks for a game
四十美分都不值的游戲上花兩百多塊
that's not even worth 40 cents.
那我們的利潤全都來自于有問題的人了
But then all our profits come from people with problems.
千萬別這么想  多想想到手的票子
Don't think aboot that. Think about all the money.
來  磕點藥放松一下
Here, have a bump of coke
好吧  但我們還是不能容忍這樣的事
Okay, but we still won't stand for this.
我不知道您是否能聽到
I don't know if you're listening,
但我覺得我體內有部分我沒法控制的東西
but I guess I have something inside me that I can't control.
某種黑暗面的東西
It's something kind of dark.
神啊  請為我指明方向
Please, help show me the way.
你召喚了誘惑之王子所為何事啊
You have summoned the prince of temptation for what purpose?
我靠  我有上癮的問題
Oh shit. Uh... I have addiction demons
我不知道該怎么辦
and I don't understand them.
那就讓我為你解釋下人性的黑暗吧
Then allow me to explain the darkness of the human soul.
你體內有多巴胺  是吧
So, you've got dopamine, right?
每次做讓你愉悅的事情例如吃東西和做愛
That's the chemical that gets released in your brain
你的大腦就會分泌這種化學物質
whenever you do something pleasurable like eating, sex.
這都是自然現象  是吧
And that's just nature, right,
和兔子啊魚啊什么的都一樣
like, rabbits and fish and shit.
它們也需要多巴胺來促使它們進食和繁殖
They need dopamine so that they want to consume and reproduce.
好吧
Okay.
但是因為人類更為進化一些
But because humans have progressed
現在又隨時有途徑獲得自己想要的東西
and now have access to all the shit they want whenever they want it,
所以很容易就會過量  導致了多巴胺問題
it's easy for them to overdo and have dopamine problems.
這也不是什么高科技
You know, it's not fucking rocket science, this stuff.
也就是說我精神上沒什么問題咯
So there's nothing spiritually wrong with me?
絕逼沒有
Fucking no.
這就和得糖尿病差不多
It's like, okay, it's like being diabetic.
就好像你不亂吃東西
You know, it's like you can eat wrong and eat wrong,
然后從肝臟分泌的化學物質就紊亂了
and chemicals get released from your liver in a weird way.
就比如不停吃谷蛋白啊什么的
You know, you've been eating gluten and shit.
然后最后肝臟分泌的化學物質就失衡了
And then eventually you've got a chemical imbalance from your liver.
突然有一天你就患上糖尿病了  對吧
And something clicked and now you're diabetic forever, right?
所以如果你一直在過度地做某些事情
So, like, if you keep doing something too much,
最終就會有多巴胺問題  對吧
eventually there's, um, a dopamine fuck up, right?
然后你的生活就一團糟了
And you're kind of screwed up for life.
這是什么意思
So what does that mean?
我可能對任何事情上癮
I can get addicted to everything
所以我就什么都不能享受了嗎
so I can't enjoy anything?
是的  差不多就是這個意思
Yeah, that's pretty much what it means.
上癮的人說我這是在填無底洞
The addict people said something about me filling a hole.
誰他媽不是在填洞呢  對吧
Well who's not filling a fucking hole, right?
這人還真是會鬼扯啊
You know? I mean, what kind of bullshit is that?
下面我們來說遺傳學
So, let's talk about genetics now.
你還想聽嗎
You still have time?
是的  你講得很棒
Yeah, no, this is great.
好的  讓我弄點輔助工具
Okay, let me get some visual aids.
稍等我片刻
Give me just a sec.
酒類市場  普通喝酒的人  喝酒上癮的人
現成的例子
Here is a fact,
80%的酒類都賣給了酗酒者
80% of alcohol sales are paid for by alcoholics.
老虎機策略  隨即支付  斯金納箱
[證明動物的學習行為是隨著強化作用刺激而發生的]
采用和老虎機同樣的策略
Using slot machine tactics,
免費游戲可以從占比例更少的
freemiums games are able to make millions off of an
免費市場  成癮者  普通玩家
手游玩家中賺到數百萬
even smaller percentage of mobile gamers.
我的天吶  他還沒完沒了了
Oh, God, he just doesn't stop.
這貨到底誰啊
Who is this guy?
新加拿大
我們在用上癮者的小額支付
We're building a new Canada
建立一個新的加拿大
with micropayments from addicts.
帶有"小額付款"功能的無聊上癮性應用
誰在乎  你以為媽逼的酒精產業在乎嗎
Who cares? You think the fucking alcohol industry cares?
他們才不在乎有10%的人會上癮
They don't care that 10% are gonna get addicted.
他們就指著這個了
They're counting on it!
我們也是一樣的
It's the same with us.
但是我們已經關注了每一個上癮玩家了
But we've got our eyes on every addict's screen.
他們每次點擊
Every button they click,
我們都會想辦法怎么讓他們花更多錢
we get feedback on how to shove this shit right down their throats.
為什么他突然聽起來像
Why does he suddenly sound like
《魔鬼代言人》里面的阿爾·帕西諾
Al Pacino in "Devil's Advocate"?
哦  我可比魔鬼壞多了
Oh, I'm much worse than the devil.
我是加拿大魔鬼  哈哈哈哈哈
I'm the Canadian devil! Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
我的天吶  是加拿大魔鬼
Oh, dear God! It's the Canadian devil!
惡魔[出自法語詞]
Beelzeboot!
你們發現了我的計劃  但是太晚了
You discovered my plan, but too late!
現在所有加拿大人的靈魂都歸我了
Now the souls of all Canadians belong to me!
-哦不  -我都做了些什么
- Oh, no! - Oh, what have I done?!
總的來說  你從你爹那里獲得的基因
So, basically, the genes you got from your dad
會讓你更容易有  呃...
make you more likely to have trouble with, um,
多巴胺調節問題
dopamine regulation,
因此你才更需要注意上癮的問題
and that's why you need to kind of watch out for addictive stuff.
那么  現在你明白了嗎  孩子
Okay, so, you kind of understand now, champ?
我想是的
I guess so.
可為什么那些公司非要做很多容易上癮的東西
But why do companies have to put so many addictive things out there?
他們都這么做  是我的授意的
You know, they all do it, and it's kind of my deal.
我必須散布誘惑
I've got to put temptation out there, too,
這樣人們就能自愿加入了
so people have free will and all that shit.
但是大家都自有一套開脫的理由
But, you know, everyone has their justification
勸自己說他們的所作所為沒有問題
and thinks what they're doing is okay.
伙計  你去哪兒了
Hey, buddy, where'd you go?
你不想再來點楓國幣嗎
Don't you want more canadough?
這是什么
What's this?
這就是讓我上癮的東西
That's what I've been addicted to.
是一款免費游戲  在給我發推送
It's a freemium game sending me push notifications.
怎么玩  就收集錢幣嗎
What, you just collect coins?
今天你能買多少錢幣
How much money can you buy today?
如果因為有趣而對某些東西上癮
No, see, if something's addictive because it's fun,
那是一回事
that's one thing.
可這明顯只是斯金納箱似的操作
But this is just blatant Skinner Box manipulation.
等等  誰推出的這個
Wait a minute, who put this out?
加拿大
Uh, Canada.
那個混賬  他總干這種不要臉的事
Oh, that son of a bitch. He's always doing this shit.
誘惑必須是微妙的
I tell him temptation has to be nuanced,
但他卻又做這些爛玩意兒
but he goes and does this crap again.
我想借用一下你的靈魂  很快歸還  孩子
I'm gonna need to borrow your soul real quick, kid.
可以嗎
Is that all right?
好吧
Okay.
過阻擋隊員  阻擋隊員
Oh, pass interference! Interference!
斯坦  你去哪
Stan? Where are you going?
我會回來的  不要阻擋我
I shall return.Do not attempt to stop me.
我早說過
Told ya.
小孩都是惡魔附身  我就沒有
Kid's got demons. I don't do that.
加拿大手機游戲部
今晚  加拿大被恐怖與悲傷籠罩
Horror and sadness all over Canada tonight.
當王子簽署制作免費游戲的同意書時
When the prince signed the agreement to make a freemium game,
他顯然是跟加拿大惡魔做了交易
he apparently made a deal with the Canadian devil.
伙計  我就是加拿大惡魔
Hey, guy! I'm the Canadian devil!
現在加拿大惡魔
Canadian devil now
已經完全控制了所有加拿大人的靈魂
has complete control of the souls of every Canadian.
這是加拿大悲劇的一天也是全世界悲劇的一天
This is a sad day for canada and, therefore, the world.
惡魔
Beelzaboot!
再說一次  你缺乏對微妙的感知
Once again, you lack any sense of nuance.
那是什么鬼東西
Who the fuck is that? well, well.
我成就非凡的同族
My over-achieving doppelganger.
你不是加拿大惡魔的對手
You're no match for Canadian Satan.
滾回你的老家去
Return from whence you came!
事情出現了令人震驚的轉折
Certainly a shocking turn of events here
真正惡魔突然出現
as the actual devil has now appeared
似乎正和加拿大惡魔戰斗
and seems to be fighting the Canadian devil.
當然  這對加拿大人是個難題
This is certainly a conundrum for Canadians everywhere
我們試圖弄清  到底應該支持誰
as we try to figure out who to root for.
就此問題來詢問一下埃德蒙頓的體育部部長
For that, let's ask the minister of sports in Edmonton.
當然  從愛國主義的角度看
Well, of course, the patriotic thing to do would be
加拿大體育部部長
應該支持加拿大惡魔
to root for the Canadian devil.
但再說一次  他也在一百萬年間
But then again, he is the one who has promised us pain
帶給了我們痛苦和奴役
and servitude for a million years.
去它的  加拿大加油
Screw that! Go Canada!
夠了惡魔  你的末日到了
Enough, Beelzaboot. Thy end has come!
-你好啊  伙計  -你好
- Hey, dude. - Hey.
你還好嗎
You all right?
是的  我覺得我會沒事的
Yeah. Yeah, I think I'm gonna be okay.
酷
Cool.
我的加拿大子民
My fellow Canadians,
作為一個國家  希望我們所作的
What we do now as a country will hopefully
成為其他國家的榜樣
be a model for others.
我們都學到了悲慘的一課
We have all learned a tragic lesson together,
那就是  世上有很多罪孽
that, though many sins are out there,
當你陷入免費游戲的泥潭
when you get involved with freemium gaming,
你就跟加拿大惡魔做了交易
you are making a deal with the Canadian devil.
我們不再做免費游戲了
We will no longer make freemium games,
我們也不想再用從上癮的人身上賺的錢
and we will no longer make improvements to our country
來修建我們的國家了
with money taken from addicts.
加拿大重新成為道德高尚  互相尊重的
Canada is back to being an ethical, respected,
寒冷的爛地方
shitty tundra.
我要這樣走  這樣走
I'm gonna move here and here,
然后我要擲骰子去殺這只僵尸
and then I'm gonna roll to kill this zombie.
好  主意不錯
Okay, good idea.
你們兩個基佬干什么呢
What are you gaywods doing?
我們在玩棋盤游戲
We're playing board games.
這樣爺爺就不去賭場  我也不玩手機游戲了
So that grandpa avoids the casino, and I avoid freemium apps.
好吧
Well, all right.
太好了  猜怎么著  我也參加
Good for you guys. Tell you what, I'll join you.
棋盤游戲配一杯酒  最合適了
Board games go good with a glass of wine.
那不是杯子  那是獎杯
That's not a glass. That's a trophy.
是你喝酒比賽贏的
That you won...for drinking.
那不是什么"喝酒"
It's not "drinking".
應該說是  快速"品嘗馨芳"  是個比賽
It's called a wine zinfandel sipping sprint, and it's competitive.
滾吧  你這該死的傲慢家伙
Get off. your high fucking horse.
該你了  爺爺  如果你的骰子擲出五或六
Your turn, grandpa. If you roll a five or six,
你就能殺這群僵尸
you can kill these zombies.
你們想押錢嗎
You guys want to put some money on it?